Finding Aid for Charles Frederick Lehmann papers, 1953-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles Frederick Lehmann papers 1953-1987
Lehmann, Charles Frederick, 1922-
4 linear feet.
861093 Aa 2
Professor of education at the University of Michigan. Files relating to his University activities, especially the Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs, and to his participation on various University committees.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Charles Lehmann (donor no. 6790 ) and came to the library in different accessions.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charles F. Lehmann was a native of Bluffton, Ohio. He received his A.B. degree from the University of Michigan in 1948. He continued his education at the University, earning his A.M. degree in history in 1955 and his Ph.D. degree in education in 1957. He served as a supervising teacher at University High School in Ann Arbor in 1948; an assistant professor at Northern Michigan College of Education in Marquette from 1948 to 1950; and a consultant in school organization and plant at the Department of Public Instruction in Lansing from 1950 to 1952. In 1953, he was invited to direct a research project at The University of Michigan sponsored by the Midwest Administration Center at the University of Chicago and funded by the Kellogg Foundation.
Lehmann joined The University of Michigan faculty in 1955 as a lecturer in the School of Education. He was named assistant professor and assistant dean of the School of Education in 1957; he was promoted to associate professor in 1959 and to professor and associate dean in 1963.
The Charles Lehmann papers relate to his University of Michigan activities and responsibilities. Many of the files pertain to his participation on the Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs and his work as associate dean of the School of Education.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Education.; University of Michigan. Senate. Advisory Committee on University Affairs.
- Correspondence files
  - Intra University
    - 1956-1959, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal and Professional Correspondence (early career)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - Associate Dean Correspondence
    - 1964 (A-Z), 3 folders (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (A-Z), 6 folders (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968 (A-B) (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968 (C-Z), 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Personal and Professional Correspondence (later career)
    - 1970-1987, 19 folders (Box 2)
  - University Administrators and Colleagues
    - Barker, Kenneth (Box 2)
    - Barnard, Ruth (Box 2)
    - Berger, Carl (Box 2)
    - Bertolaet, Frederick (Box 2)
    - Biddle, Bruce (Box 2)
    - Cohen, Wilbur (Box 2)
    - Davidge, Lyn (Box 2)
    - Fleming, Robben W. (Box 2)
    - Frye, Billy (Box 2)
    - Rhodes, Frank (Box 2)
    - Rubin, Norman (Box 2)
    - Shapiro, Harold (Box 2)
    - Smith, Allan (Box 2)
    - Stark, Joan (Box 2)
- General Topical File
  - Center for the Continuing Education of Women (Box 2)
  - Dicken School (Box 2)
  - Geography Dept. discontinuance (Box 2)
  - Institute for Human Adjustment, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Plant Operation Review (Box 2)
  - Public Instruction, Dept. of, 1953-1957 (Box 2)
  - Saturday Seminar Series, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - School of Education Appraisal Committee (Box 2)
- Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs
  (include Senate Assembly activities)
  - Meeting Files
    - 1975, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - 1976, 9 folders (Box 3)
    - 1977, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - 1977, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - 1978, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Topical Files
    - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Committee on Economic Status of the Faculty, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Dearborn Meeting, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Faculty Handbook, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Nominating Committee, 1978 (Box 4)
    - Rules and Organization of the University Senate (Box 4)
    - Senate Assembly, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Tenure, 1977